本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
我觉得是 B5
I'm gonna say b-five.
错
Miss!
我不觉得你的下法符合规则
I don't think you're playing this right.
孩子们  快过来
Kids! Come quick!
我想让你们和我一起乐一乐
I need you to laugh at this with me!
是谁可爱得要死  是你们永远的朋友
Who's cute as a button, and always your friend?
小  吉  迪  恩
'Lil G-I-D to the E-O-N!
眨眼
Wink!
小吉迪恩
Lil' Gideon.
啊  吉迪恩
Ugh, Gideon.
还记得我不愿意和他约会
Remember when I wouldn't date him,
然后他想要把我们杀了吗
And he tried to destroy us?
他一直都想着法地忽悠我让我失去神秘小屋
He's always trying to trick me into losing the Mystery Shack!
有一次  我抓到他偷我的润肤膏
One time, I caught him stealing my moisturizer.
但是  我们对他共同的憎恶将我们紧密地团结在一起
And yet, our mutual hatred for him bonds us together.
快来到
Come on down to
小吉迪恩的心灵帐篷吧
'Lil Gideon's tent of telepathy.
很快会在此地开业
Opening soon at this location.
呃  我们是不是应该为此感到担心
Uh, should we be worried about that?
算了吧  吉迪恩唯一能夺下这个小屋的办法是
Please. The only way Gideon's taking over this shack
闯进来偷走我的地契
is by breaking in and stealing my deed.
你是说  现在吗
You mean like right now?
呃  三十八
Uh, thirty-eight?
四十一  噢  老天
Forty-one? Oh, heavens to Betsy!
吉迪恩
Gideon!
啧啧  斯坦福
Well, well, Stanford!
我最大的死对头
My arch nemesis.
似乎我们已经卷入了
We seem to have entered
一场危险的猫鼠游戏之中
a dangerous game of cat and mouse.
但问题就是
But the question remains,
到底谁是猫  谁是
Who is the cat, and who is the--
苏斯  扫帚
Soos, broom.
噢  不  不要用扫帚
Oh, no, not the broom!
你记住我的话  斯坦福
You mark my words, Stanford!
总有一天我会得到密码的
One day I'm gonna get that combination!
等我偷走你的地契
And once I steal that deed
你就要跟神秘小屋永别了
You'll never see the Mystery Shack again!
祝你好运  小子
Good luck, bucko!
哈  这个藏着保险箱密码的地方
Ha! The combo to this safe is in the one place
他永远找不到  在我大脑里
he'll never find it, my brain!
你的大脑没有你想的那么保险  斯坦福・派恩斯
Your brain isn't as safe as you might think, Stanford Pines!
这就是我的最后一招了
This is the last straw.
是时候解锁这本日志最大的秘密了
It's time to unlock the journal's greatest secret.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
CC录制： ufohaman  Qin Cong
时间轴： WaitinZ
■
翻译： wesyman  不远景  Enpistu
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第一季第十九集
Gravity Falls  S01E19  Dreamscaperers
他是“老”西部的代表
He put the "old" in old west.
人们把他叫做  老顽童爷爷
They call him... Grandpa the Kid!
我白天总是很困
I'm tired during the day.
我感同身受
I can relate to this.
斯坦叔公  我们为什么就不能看一部
Grunkle Stan, why can't we watch a movie
大家都喜欢的电影 《梦幻男生高中》
that we'll all enjoy? Dream Boy High!
在这里  爱永恒地刻在你的唱片上哦
Where love is on your permanent record.
不要
Boo!
你们看了就会慢慢喜欢上的
You'll learn to like it.
伙计们  厨房里有一只蝙蝠
Dudes! There's a bat in the kitchen!
它想用它奇怪的小蝙蝠爪子摸我
It tried to touch me with its weird little bat fingers.
别担心  一切尽在我掌控中
Don't worry, I got this under control.
迪普  去解决这个问题
Dipper, take care of it.
好
Yes!
什么  为什么不能是梅宝去做
What? Why can't Mabel do it?
因为人生就是不公平的
'Cause life ain't fair.
快去赶走蝙蝠  让我们能好好看电视
Now go fight a bat so we can watch tv.
不行  斯坦叔公
No way, Grunkle Stan.
你总是让我去做愚蠢的杂活
You always make me do dumb chores.
这次我坚决不干
I'm putting my foot down this time.
我说  小子  现在就去做
I said, do it, kid! Now!
好吧  我来做
Okay, I'll do it!
愚蠢的杂活
Stupid chores.
记住  是蝙蝠更害怕你  不是你更害怕它
Remember, bats are more afraid of you than you are of them.
好像我说的是小鸭子
Maybe I'm thinking of ducklings.
小鸭子  嘎嘎
Ducklings. Quack, quack.
嘎嘎嘎
Quack, quack, quack.
涂上消毒剂
Swabbin' on disinfectant. Doo-do-doo.
斯坦叔公为什么总是叫我
Why does Grunkle Stan always pick on me?
想想吧  越是烦人  困难的杂活
Think about it, the more painful or difficult the chore is,
越是要让我来做
The more likely it is I'll have to do it.
他为什么就不叫你们呢
Why doesn't he pick on you guys?
迪普  斯坦的性格是世上最难捉摸的东西之一
Dipper, Stan's personality is one of life's great mysteries.
就像你能不能舔到自己的手肘这个问题一样
Like whether or not it's possible to lick your own elbow.
-我赌你不行  -我赌我可以
- I bet you can't. - I bet I can.
舔手肘  舔手肘
Lick it! Lick it!
舔手肘
Lick it!
有时我感觉斯坦讨厌我
Sometimes I feel like Stan hates me.
水槽堵了
The sink's clogged!
迪普  过来给我修好
Dipper, get in here and fix it!
你觉得密码在你脑子里就是安全的吗  斯坦福
You think that combination's safe in your mind, Stanford?
我们来看看我的新仆人是怎么想的吧
We'll see what my new minion has to say about that.
三角形  遵吾召唤
"Triangulum. Entangulum.
心灵之障  秘密严防
"Veneforis dominus ventium.
从吾之令  摧毁屏障
Veneforis venetisarium!"
舔手肘  舔手肘
Lick that elbow! Lick that elbow!
手肘总是在逃避我  就像无垠的地平线一样
Like the infinite horizon, it eludes my grasp.
这声音是不是我想到的那个人
Is that who I think it is?
噢  重力泉  回来真好
Oh! Oh! Gravity Falls, it is good to be back!
我的名字是  比尔・赛弗
Name's Bill Cipher.
我猜想你是某种
And I take it you're some kind
活生生的腹语娃娃
of living ventriloquist dummy?
只是开个玩笑
I'm just kidding,
我知道你是谁  吉迪恩
I know who you are, Gideon.
你  你是什么东西
What-- what are you?
怎  怎么知道我的名字
H-- how do you know my name?
噢  我知道很多东西
Oh, I know lot of things.
很多东西
Lots of things.
嘿  瞧瞧我的本领吧
Hey, look what I can do.
小子  鹿的牙齿送给你
Deer teeth, for you, kid!
你是个疯子
You're insane!
我当然是疯子  你有什么意见
Sure, I am! What's your point?
听我说  魔鬼
Listen to me, demon!
我有工作让你做
I have a job for you!
我需要你进入斯坦福・派恩斯的大脑
I need you to enter the mind of Stanford Pines
偷走他保险箱的密码
And steal the code to his safe!
等等
Wait.
斯坦・派恩斯
Stan Pines.
你猜怎么着  小子  你说服我了
You know what, kid, you've convinced me.
我出卖自己
I'm sold!
我会帮你解决这件事的  作为报酬
I'll help you with this, and in return,
你可以帮助我做一件我一直在做的事情
You can help me with something I've been working on.
细节我们稍后再谈
We'll work out the details later.
成交
Deal.
好的  是时候入侵斯坦的大脑了
Well, time to invade Stan's mind.
一定很有趣
This should be fun!
记住  现实只是一个幻象
Remember, reality is an illusion,
宇宙只是一个全息图像  买黄金吧
The universe is a hologram, buy gold!
再见
Bye!
成功了
It worked!
不  抱歉
No. Sorry.
那家伙脑子里在想些什么啊
What is going on in that guy's head?
迪普
Dipper!
我们必须帮帮斯坦
We've gotta help Stan!
等等  什么
Wait, what?
一个邪恶的三角形的家伙
This evil triangle guy
说他要闯入斯坦的大脑
said he's gonna break into Stan's mind,
偷走他保险箱的密码
And steal the combination to his safe!
而且  我们回来的路上还去买了点零食
Also, we stopped for snacks on the way here.
三角形的家伙
Triangle guy?
我感觉我以前在日志里见过类似的东西
I feel like I've seen something like this before in the journal.
小心比尔
"Beware Bill.
他是我所遇上的
"The most powerful and dangerous creature
最强大和危险的生物
"I've ever encountered.
千万不要召唤！
不管你做什么  不要让他进入你的大脑
Whatever you do, never let him into your mind."
斯坦叔公
Grunkle Stan!
可以跟随这个魔鬼
"It is possible to follow the demon
进入一个人的大脑并阻止他制造混乱
"Into a person's mind and prevent his chaos.
只需吟唱以下咒语
One must simply recite this incantation."
这真是太好了
This is just great.
我一整天都在为斯坦清理水槽和对付蝙蝠
I spend all day cleaning sinks and fighting bats for Stan,
现在我还得从什么疯狂的脑魔手中拯救他
And now I have to save him from some crazy brain demon?
但如果我们不采取行动的话
But if we don't do anything,
吉迪恩可能会偷走小屋  或者发生更糟糕的事情
Gideon might steal the shack, or worse!
好吧
Fine.
准备好  伙计们  我们即将开始旅程
Get ready, guys. We're about to journey
进入我们前所未见的  世界上最恐怖
into the most horrifying, disturbing place
最令人讨厌的地方
any of us have ever been.
叔公的大脑
Our uncle's mind.
你们觉得我可以把这些煎饼片带进斯坦的大脑里吗
You think I can take these burrito bites into Stan's brain?
可以还是不可以
Thumbs up, thumbs down?
知道吗  我会把它带进去的
You know what? I'm just gonna bring them.
好吧  伙计们
Okay, guys.
为了救我们叔公
In order to save our uncle,
我们必须跟着那只梦魔进入他的意识
we're gonna have to follow that dream demon into his mind.
我很好奇斯坦现在在想什么
I wonder what Stan's thinking about right now.
我爱苏斯就像爱自己的儿子一样
I love Soos like a son.
苏斯  这是很严肃的事情
Soos! This is serious!
对唔
Sowee.
我们行动吧
Let's do this!
无尽之信念
"Fidentus omnium.
心灵之主宰
"Magis omentium.
马格捏西姆  阿德哈米南
"Magnesuim adharminum.
伟大的杰作
"Magnum opus.
愿你占据躯体
"Habeas corpus.
（注：此句为“盗梦空间  诺兰  赞誉过度”的拉丁化）
因塞克特  诺拉纳斯  奥菲瑞特
"Inceptus Nolanus overratus.
心灵之主  心灵之主
"Magis tremensium. Magis tremensium.
心灵之主
Magis tremensium!"
哦  天啊
Oh, wow! Whoa!
我了个
Oh, what the--
这就是斯坦的意识吗
Whoa! This is Stan's mind?
总感觉这里应该有很多漂亮的老太太
Huh. Figured there would be a lot more hot old ladies.
记住了各位
Remember, everyone,
我们得小心那个三角形的家伙
We've got to look out for the triangle guy.
是啊  小心那个三角形的家伙
Yeah, look out for the triangle guy!
是他  就是这家伙
It's him! It's the guy!
不准在叔公的大脑里搞破坏
You leave our uncle's brain alone,
你这等腰三角怪物
You isosceles monster!
抓住你了
Gotcha!
等等  怎么会
Wait. What?
啊  斯坦的家人  我们最终还是见面了
Ah, Stan's family, we meet at last.
问号  流星  松树
Question mark, shooting star, pine tree,
我总有一种会见到你们的预感
I had a hunch I might bump into you.
梅宝
Mabel!
你究竟要在斯坦叔公的意识里找什么
What do you want with our uncle's mind anyway?
哦  就要他保险箱的密码啊
Oh, just the code to the old man's safe!
小屋里面是由代表你们叔公记忆的
Inside the shack is a maze of a thousand doors
上千道门组成的迷宫
representing your uncle's memories.
其中一道门后面有他输入密码的记忆
Behind one of them is a memory of him inputting the code.
所以我只需要找到它
I just need to find it
吉迪恩就会很豪爽地报答我的
and Gideon will pay me handsomely!
除非我们能阻止你
Not if we stop you!
哈  你们没机会的
Ha! Fat chance!
我是意识之王
I'm the master of the mind.
我甚至知道你现在在想什么
I even know what you're thinking right now.
这不可能
That's impossible!
谁也猜不出来我在想什么
No one can guess what I'm thinking!
我们这是在哪儿啊  哥们儿
Whoa! Where are we, bro?
我们一定是在天堂  因为我看到了一个天使
We must be in heaven, 'cause I just saw an angel.
我永远都不会放开你的腿的
I'm never letting go of your leg!
你们来错地方了  孩子们
You're out of your league, kids.
在看到可能令你们后悔的事情前赶快回去
Turn around now, before you see something you might regret.
再会了  傻瓜们
Later, suckers!
我们要进屋了
We're going in.
梅宝  咱能把那两个人留在外面么
Mabel, can we leave those guys out here?
看着他们有点刺眼睛
Looking at them hurts my eyes.
不  他们可以帮忙
No! They can help us!
必须的  抬轿子
Totally! Arm throne!
哥们儿  抬轿子
Dude, arm throne!
-抬轿子  -啊
- Arm throne! - Ah!
-哇  -好惊人
- Whoa! - Neato!
-好炫  -我也觉得很炫
- Radical! - I also think it's radical!
不退款  不退款
No refunds! No refunds!
看啊  斯坦的全部记忆
Whoa, look! All of Stan's memories.
这下好了  这里一定有数不过来的
Great, sure there's plenty of memories
斯坦支使我的记忆
of Stan bossing me around.
我好想看啊
Can't wait to see more of that!
拜托  迪普
Come on, Dipper.
我们得赶在比尔之前找到保险箱的密码
We've gotta find the code before Bill does.
梅宝在说话
Mabel is talking!
好有范儿
So rad!
我们开始找吧
Let's get searching!
乔治  瑞科
Jorge, Rico,
你们俩是一个人所能结交到的最好的
You're the two best Colombian prison friends
哥伦比亚裔狱友
a fella could make.
我想让他去死
没错
不在这儿
Nope.
先生  请问您愿意购买一台斯坦牌吸尘器吗
Sir, would you like to buy a Stan Vac vacuum?
斯坦吸尘器  比任何东西都能吸
Stan Vac. It sucks more than anything.
（注：也有“世界上最逊的东西”的意思）
广告语还得改改
Gotta work on that.
不在这儿
Nope.
哇  斯坦在约会
Whoa! It's Stan on a date!
那个  你的眼睛很奇怪
So, your, uh, your eye is weird.
我们  我们来谈谈这个吧
Let's, let's talk about that.
形势不妙
This is going terrible.
我想不出该说什么
I can't think of anything to say,
而且她在近处看起来很诡异
And she looks weird up close.
得想办法逃出去
Think of a way out.
没有什么特定的借口
Non-specific excuse!
受不了
Yeesh!
大家快看啊  关于我的记忆
Look, guys. Memories about me.
我觉得这不是个好主意
That doesn't seem like a good idea.
我只是想知道那老头子到底是怎么看我的
I just want to know what the old guy really thinks of me.
我们不是已经知道斯坦对我们的感情了吗
We already know how Stan feels about us,
他爱我们  我们好棒的
He loves us! We're great.
是的  我们接着找吧
Yeah, let's just keep moving.
还要走  太好了
More moving? Yes!
我喜欢动感
I love motion!
好的  就看一眼
Okay, just a quick peek.
迪普  我后背痒  你能挠到吗
Dipper, my back itches, can you scratch it?
迪普  去刷水壶
Dipper, clean the boiler!
不许顶嘴
No buts!
还不快去劈柴
Now go chop that firewood already!
斯坦  我一直想问你
Dude, Stan, I been meaning to ask you.
你为什么一直和迪普过不去
Why are you so hard on Dipper all the time?
好吧  苏斯  我要告诉你一些事情
Look, Soos, I'm gonna let you in on something.
想知道我的真正想法吗
You wanna know what I really think?
那孩子是个废物  弱爆了
The kid's a loser. He's weak.
他从头到脚透出的都是困窘
He's an utter embarrassment.
我恨不得赶紧甩掉他
I just want to get rid of him.
你好  斯坦保险箱的密码  你在哪儿
Hello, code to Stan's safe, where are you?
开门关门真好玩
Opening and closing doors is fun.
我也能做到
I can do it also!
如果人们知道
If only people knew the truth.
藏在这台贩卖机后面的真相
That hidden behind this vending machine,
-我秘密地藏着  -无聊
- I secretly have a - boring!
好啦各位
All right, guys,
我对这扇门有很好的预感哦
I have a good feeling about this door.
嘿  肚皮先生
Hey, mr. Tummy.
您好  斯坦先生
Hey, mr. Stan!
你饿吗
Are you hungry?
我饿
Yes.
-吃饼干吧  -呃
- Eat your crackers! - Ugh!
天啊
Sweet sally.
我们找好半天了
Oh, we've been searching forever.
如果那个三角形的家伙已经找到了密码就坏了
What if the triangle guy finds the memory before we do?
如果我们想找到斯坦的记忆  就要像斯坦一样思考
If we wanna find Stan's memory, we gotta think like Stan.
他总是在藏东西  是吧
He's always hiding stuff, right?
是啊  比如他把他的逮捕令藏在
Yeah, like how he hides his arrest warrants
纪念品店的地毯下面
under that rug in the gift shop?
苏斯  你说对了  看啊
Soos, that's it! Look!
就放这儿了
There ya go.
然后我来输入密码
And now to input the code.
十三  四十四  最后是
Thirteen, forty-four, and finally--
各位  我们找到了
Dude, we found it! Yeah!
现在我们怎么办
But what do we do now?
扫把星
Jinx!
嗯  我们得在比尔发现前
Um, um, let's just destroy the door
摧毁这扇门
Before bill can find it.
等一下  或许应该我出手
Wait! Maybe I should do it!
我又大又肥的胳膊最适合摧毁东西了
My big fat arms are great at destroying stuff.
哦  那好
Oh, okay.
嘿  各位
Hey, guys!
我刚刚看到一段斯坦的记忆
I just saw a memory of Stan
关于穿着短裤滑旱冰的
roller skating and wearing short-shorts!
看起来还不算糟
Didn't look--didn't look half bad.
这里的气氛很诡异
Hey, something weird is going on here.
天啊  你们这群孩子太好骗了
Boy, you kids sure are gullible!
我就知道你们会帮我找到密码
I knew you'd lead me straight to the code!
你们还真是笨得可笑
It's funny how dumb you are.
斯坦的保险箱密码
The combination to Stan's safe!
简直比我想象的还容易
Boy, that was even easier than I thought.
哦  是吗
Oh, yeah?
那好  你就是个
Well, you're a...
混蛋
A stink-face!
梅宝  回击得好棒
Awesome comeback, Mabel!
塞勒  别拿我当小朋友
Don't treat me like a child, Xyler.
再会了  傻瓜们
Later, suckers!
快走  我们得去救斯坦
Come on, we've got to save Stan!
有什么意义呢
What's the point?
我为什么要救他
Why should I save him, huh?
我为斯坦没日没夜的工作
I work for stan day and night,
可是作为回报  他就只有一句想甩掉我而已
And all he does in return is say he wants to get rid of me.
迪普  一定不是你想的那样
Dipper, I'm sure that's not true.
我在他的记忆里亲眼看到的  梅宝
I saw it with my own eyes in one of his memories, Mabel!
我现在知道他为什么总是找我麻烦了
He's always picked on me and now I know why!
斯坦讨厌我
Stan hates me!
迪普  不管你看到了什么
Dipper, it doesn't matter what you saw.
如果我们不能阻止比尔  我们就会丢掉神秘小屋
If we don't stop Bill, we'll lose the shack!
那又怎样  我不干了
No, you know what? Not this time.
这次斯坦的问题我不会帮他解决
For once, this is one of Stan's problems I'm not gonna fix.
好  过来  苏斯
Fine! Come on, Soos.
我们自己去救斯坦
We'll save Stan ourselves!
迪普  你一直很酷  但这样不对啊  哥们儿
Dipper, you're a cool dude, but this isn't cool, dude.
我们走  塞勒
Let's go, Xyler!
好的  克莱兹
All right, Craz!
这是我们的名字
Those are our names!
-喂  -比尔
- Yello? - Bill!
你找到有密码的记忆了吗
Did you find the memory with the combination yet?
放松点  矮个子  就在我这里呢
Relax, shortstack, I got it right here.
太好了
Perfect!
快把它给我
Now give it to me
之后我会履行我的承诺
And I'll fulfill my end of the bargain.
终于啊  密码是  你有笔吗
Finally! It's-- you got a pen there?
密码是十三  四十四
It's thirteen, forty-four--
不不  等等  不要
Ah! No, no, wait! No!
没有哪个比无底洞更深不见底
None more bottomless than the bottomless pit.
也就是你们现在看到的这个  它是深不见底的
Which, as you can see here, is bottomless.
哇  无论那是什么东西  它再也回不来了
Whoo! Whatever that was, it's gone forever.
哈哈  砰
Ha ha! Boom!
梅宝成功了
Mabel did it!
小屋安全了
The shack is safe!
这笔交易取消了
The deal's off!
等一下  不  等一下
Wait. No! Wait!
现在我要改用替代计划
I'm switching to plan b!
你们
You!
你们根本想象不到你们害我失去了什么
You can't even imagine what you just cost me!
你们知道把我惹毛了
Do you have any idea what I'm like
有什么后果吗
when I'm mad?
看来他生气的时候会变得相当疯狂
So I guess he gets really mad when he gets mad.
面对噩梦吧
Eat nightmares!
我该怎么离开这个地方
How do I get out of this place?
出口  你在哪儿
Exit? Hello?
啊  又是这里
Ah, this again?
他是个废物  弱爆了
He's a loser. He's weak.
我恨不得赶紧甩掉他
I just want to get rid of him.
对  在我小时候人们总是这么说我的
Yeah, those are all things people said about me when I was a boy.
啊
Huh?
糟糕透了
It was terrible.
我是运动场上的大窝囊废
I was the biggest wimp on the playground.
所以一年夏天  我老爹给我报名了拳击课
So one summer my pop signs me up for boxing lessons.
那情况简直比学校操场上还糟
And it was even worse than the schoolyard!
左勾拳
Left hook!
知道吗  那时候我以为老爹是想折磨我
You know, at the time, I thought my pop was trying to torture me.
但是你猜怎么着
But wouldn't you know it?
老头子自始至终都是在帮我的忙
The old man was doin' me a favor all along.
把包给我
Give me that bag!
救命  我的钱包
Help! My purse!
-救命  -左勾拳
- Help! - Left hook!
你明白了吗
So you see?
所以我对迪普这么严厉
That's why I'm hard on Dipper.
为了让他坚强起来
To toughen him up,
这样当世界来者不善时  他才能反击回去
So when the world fights, he fights back.
你觉得这样做有用吗
Do you think it's actually working?
我成功了
I, I did it!
太好啦
Yes!
他真的进步很快
He's really comin' along.
在关键时刻  其实我对他感到很自豪
When push comes to shove, I'm actually proud of him.
可别把这些告诉他
Just don't ever tell him that.
他的脑袋现在已经够大的了
His head's big enough as it is.
说得对
That's true.
哇  小子  你在这里做什么
Whoa, kid, what are you doin' here?
顺便说一句  胸前的洞不错啊
Nice hole in your chest, by the way.
来把它填上
Let's fix that up.
什么  你是怎么做到的
W-- what the-- how did you do that?
一句话  小子  我们在意识里面
Word to the wise, kid, we're in the mind.
在这里你可以想什么有什么
You could do whatever you can imagine in here.
嗯  可不是吗
Well, how about that.
不  快停下
No! Make it stop!
救命  快来人啊
Help! Someone, please!
天啊  我在干什么呢
Oh, my gosh, what am I doing?
我得去阻止比尔
I gotta stop Bill!
哈  要反击了
Huh. Fightin' back.
一个噩梦要来了
One nightmare, coming up!
噩梦
Nightmare?
希望他指的不是那只英国绅士狗
Hope he doesn't mean that British dog-man
我总是梦到它
I'm always dreaming about.
好啊  好啊  好啊
'Ello, 'ello, 'ello!
谁往补丁里插了个棍子啊
Who's crike for a shdig in the pudding?
这就是我所害怕的一切啊
Ah! It's everything I ever feared!
到你了
You!
啊  可爱的我
Ahh! My cuteness!
你对可爱的我做了什么
What did you do to my cuteness--
接下来是你们
You're next!
酷  接下来是我们
Cool, we're next!
我的梦幻男生
My dream boys!
现在该解决你们了  彻底解决
And now to finish you off, for once and for all!
不  不
No! No!
不要
Dude, no!
喂  比尔
Hey, Bill!
什么
What!
领结不错
Nice bowtie!
-迪普  -哥们儿
- Dipper! - Dude!
伙计们  我刚刚知道
Guys! I just learned that you can conjure
在斯坦的精神世界里  你可以实现所有的构想
whatever you can conceive in Grunkle Stan's mindscape!
啊
Huh?
就是想一些帅气的战斗招式  它们会变成真的
Just think of cool fighting stuff and it'll happen!
就像这样
Like this.
现在他死啦
He's dead now.
什么  是谁告诉你的
What? Who told you that?
别信他的话
Don't listen to him!
我们想做什么都可以吗
We can do anything?
比如用小猫咪当拳头
Like have kittens for fists?
你们好呀  小伙伴
Well, hello, friends!
什么都行  是吧
Anything, huh?
苏斯最爱肚肚光波
Soos loves stomach beam stare!
玩够了
Enough games!
仓鼠球护盾  激活
Hamster ball shields, activate!
激活
Activate!
啊  我的眼睛
Ah, my eye!
升起来  塞勒  升起来  克莱兹
Rise, Xyler! Rise, Craz!
不  合成音乐
No! Synthesized music!
好刺耳
It hurts!
现在要来想象出你最可怕的噩梦
And now to imagine your worst nightmare!
离开斯坦意识的传送门
A portal out of Stan's mind!
离开斯坦的意识
Out of Stan's mind!
梅宝  各位
Mabel! Everyone!
一起来
Together!
不  不  不
No, no, no!
够了
Enough!
好吧  你们几个令我印象深刻
You know, I'm impressed with you guys.
你们比看上去的样子聪明多了
You're a lot more clever than you look.
尤其是那个胖子
Especially the fat one.
他在说你呢
He's talking about you.
所以我这次就放过你们几个小鬼
So I'm gonna let you kids off the hook.
之后你们可能还派得上用场
You might come in handy later.
不过记住这个
But know this.
黑暗正在接近
A darkness approaches,
在即将到来的某一天
A day will come in the future
你所关心的一切都会改变
when everything you care about will change.
在此之前  我会注视着你们的
Until then, I'll be watching you.
我会注视着你们
I'll be watching you.
他不见了  我们成功啦
He's gone, we did it!
怎么
Wha--
一定是斯坦要醒了
Stan must be waking up.
我还能再见到你们吗
Will I ever see you guys again?
在你的梦里
In your dreams.
说得好  兄弟  说得好
Good one, bro. Good one.
我们成功了
We did it!
什么  什么成功了
What? Did what?
你们都在这里做什么
What are you all doing here?
还有我为什么会梦到
And why was I dreaming of
两个色彩鲜艳的叛逆小伙子
two brightly colored and radical young men?
斯坦叔公  你没事
Grunkle Stan! You're okay!
这是什么  拥抱吗
What is this, a hug?
不
Nope.
是锁喉
It's a choke hold.
干得不错  孩子  干得不错
Not bad, kid. Not bad.
我很庆幸吉迪恩没有成功入侵保险柜
I'm just glad Gideon didn't get into the safe.
我真的很爱这间老屋子
I really love this old shack.
大家抱一个
Group hug!
不要吗
No?
我总是掌握不好时机
I never know the right time!
你们有没有感觉到
Hey, do you guys feel a--
抱歉啊  派恩斯一家  我吵醒你们了吗
Oh, I'm sorry, Pines family, did I wake you?
但是我们打败了比尔
But we defeated Bill.
比尔辜负了我
Bill failed me!
所以我改用替代计划
So I switched to plan b.
炸药
Dynamite.
什么  比尔
What? Bill?
谁  你们几个在说什么
Who-- wh-- what are you guys talking about?
剧透啦  斯坦福  我拿到地契了
Spoiler alert, Stanford. I've got the deed!
神秘小屋是我的啦
The mystery shack belongs to me!
所以  滚出我的财产
So, get off my property!
老爸
Daddy?
把它开到前面来
Bring it around the front.
各位  别担心
Don't worry, guys.
这不过是梦里的一部分
It's just part of the dream.
我们随时都可能醒来
We're going to wake up any second now.
对吗  对吗
Right? Right?
快来人掐我一下啊
Someone, pinch me, dude.
未完待续...